<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>vim on Rafael Leyva Ruiz</title><link>https://rafaelleru.github.io/tags/vim/</link><description>Recent content in vim on Rafael Leyva Ruiz</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rafaelleru.github.io/tags/vim/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>09 - Use custom python paths on neovim lsp client</title><link>https://rafaelleru.github.io/blog/09-custom-python-paths-nvim-lsp/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafaelleru.github.io/blog/09-custom-python-paths-nvim-lsp/</guid><description>Recently we started to use airflow in my current company, and I found an issue, LSP was not recognisin our custom plugins and DAGS inside of the airflow folder. This was caused because airflow is also a package that is installed in my virtualenv, so jedi was not able to discover definitions for example.
That was caused because in my PYTHONPATH airflow was a package, so jedi was not looking into the airflow folder for more source code, causing LSP functionality to not work fine.</description></item><item><title>06 - Toggle vim QuickFix list, the right way</title><link>https://rafaelleru.github.io/blog/06-quickfix-autocomands/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafaelleru.github.io/blog/06-quickfix-autocomands/</guid><description>The Primeagean has a great video talking about all the great things you can get by using QuickFix lists and local QuickFix lists. After watching it I quickly grab the following code and paste it to my config.
let g:the_primeagen_qf_l = 0 let g:the_primeagen_qf_g = 0 fun! ToggleQFList(global) if a:global if g:the_primeagen_qf_g == 1 let g:the_primeagen_qf_g = 0 cclose else let g:the_primeagen_qf_g = 1 copen end else if g:the_primeagen_qf_l == 1 let g:the_primeagen_qf_l = 0 lclose else let g:the_primeagen_qf_l = 1 lopen end endif endfun This code will allow us to toggle both the LocalFix list and the QuickFix list by calling this function.</description></item><item><title>05 - JSON magic with VIM</title><link>https://rafaelleru.github.io/blog/05-json-magic-vim/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rafaelleru.github.io/blog/05-json-magic-vim/</guid><description>How to edit, compare, and pretty format JSONs only with VIM (and maybe some other CLI tool) I have been comparing multiple versions of the same JSON file in my daily workflow, having to edit it and converting it from one line to pretty and vice-versa. For that purpose, I was copying the JSON to a website called JSON formatter and validator (There are hundreds of sites with the same objective around in the internet) and then comparing it to his also prettified version using JSON diff.</description></item></channel></rss>