<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ansible on Rafael Leyva Ruiz</title><link>https://rafaelleru.github.io/tags/ansible/</link><description>Recent content in ansible on Rafael Leyva Ruiz</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rafaelleru.github.io/tags/ansible/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Managing dotfiles with Ansible (II)</title><link>https://rafaelleru.github.io/blog/ansibleii/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://rafaelleru.github.io/blog/ansibleii/</guid><description>Apart from linking my config files, I needed to build and install a bunch of programs in each new machine I set up, so I was using some bash scripts. I decided to use ansible for this task because it fits perfectly my needs to do this.
In this post, there are some examples of programs I am building manually with ansible, my reasons, and some thoughts.
1. Building my neovim copy → The neovim role By default ubuntu repositories have a very old neovim version (the last time I installed neovim from ubuntu LSP was not available, but it was ready in the master branch of the project).</description></item><item><title>Managing dotfiles with Ansible</title><link>https://rafaelleru.github.io/blog/dotfiles-ansible-i/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://rafaelleru.github.io/blog/dotfiles-ansible-i/</guid><description>1. Why Ansible Ansible is a standard in the industry to automate deployments and provision virtual machines in the DevOps landscape. The main reason to use ansible to manage my dotfiles was to learn how to use it.
Yes, Ansible seems to be overkill for this purpose. Dotbot seems to be a much smaller tool. Also, Greg Hurrel has created a config framework called fig, bothered for the size and bloat that Ansible represents.</description></item></channel></rss>